A Guide to the Joseph Crosby Lincoln Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6336-a
Joseph Crosby Lincoln Collection 1905-1940
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6336-a
27 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, 1965 March 23
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - Selection from Storm Signals, read 1936 March 29, [1935]; TMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to ( ? Charles A.) Burkhardt, 1905 Apr 24; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accepts invitation to meeting of the American Booksellers' Association on May 16, 1905. Mentions Mr. Pratt.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Mr. Moffatt, 1920 Apr 26; ALS, 2 p.
    [Regrets that he cannot take part in the excursion due to a business engagement, but knows that Moffatt has plenty of entertainers and that "I have read my fellow Hackensackers to death." Sends "regrets and regards" to Dan Beard and [Hamlin] Garland. ]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Arthur Turner Vance, 1921 Jul 11; ALS, 3 p.
    [Expresses reluctance to go to New York due to the hot weather and the pressures of his next book. Asks Vance to thank Mr. Anderson for his
    Galusha the Magnificent
    pictures, which he praises. Requests that Vance press the
    Pictorial Review
    financial department to send the last installment of the
    payment. Suggests eating together if he gets to New York. Asks about Vance's vacation plans.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Mr. Wheeler, 1927 Dec 6; TLS, 1 p.
    [Explains that Cape Cod is the locale for his stories because he knows and likes the area. Says his characters are all composites of people he has known.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Hamilton Holt, 1932 May 29; TLS, 1 p.
    [Regrets that he and his wife [ Florence Sargent Lincoln] cannot donate to Rollins College because "the appeals here at home are overwhelming... in these distressful times [the Depression]."]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Mr. Munson, 1934 Jun 10; ALS, 3 p.
    [Details the basic idea behind
    Shavings
    , which took six or seven months to write. Says people like the main character J. Edgar W. (Jed) Winslow and that the book is one of his most popular. Mentions a dramatization of it by Henry Wilson Savage, starring Harry Beresford, which had good runs in New York and on the circuit. Says he looks forward to reading Munson's book.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Hamilton Holt, 1936 Mar 21; ALS, 2 p.
    [Regrets that he won't be with Holt to honor Franklin D. Roosevelt. Says that if Roosevelt is even half as proud of his honorary degree as Joseph Crosby Lincoln is of his, he will return to Washington"with his chest wall extended." Mentions Florence Sargent Lincoln. ]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Lichtig and Englander, 1936 Sep 17; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says he hopes that Paramount Pictures Corporation's interest in
    Queer Judson
    for Cooper will lead to something.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Frank J. Beebee, 1939 May 25; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says he hasn't been well. Thanks Beebee for the monogram. Says he does the work extremely well.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Frank J. Beebee, 1939 Jun 20; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says their letters must have crossed, as he remembers writing Beebee about his "dainty and well executed" monogram. Says he will send Beebee the autographed photograph he asked for when the ones he requested from his publisher arrive.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Frank J. Beebee, 1939 Nov 23; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says that the photographs have been ordered from his publisher and that he will send Beebee one when they arrive.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Hamilton Holt, 1940 Jun 11; TLS, 1 p.
    [Mentions a recurrence of bronchitis and questions how well he could read aloud in Woodstock, CT., by July. Says he might be able to read a few of his Cape Cod verses but hopes to know better by July 1. Mentions Florence Sargent Lincoln. ]
  - Hamilton Holt to Joseph Crosby Lincoln, 1940 Jun 19; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Asks if Lincoln could come on either July 21 or 28 to do a reading. Says he would be glad to have him and his wife Florence Sargent Lincoln as his guests for the weekend. Regrets not being able to pay anything except traveling expenses, as the proceeds will go toward the restoration of a church. Mentions having Arthur Guiterman, Irving A. Bacheller, and the Bloch Quartet the previous year. Encloses a leaflet about the church (not included with letter).]
  - Hamilton Holt to Joseph Crosby Lincoln, 1940 Jun 20; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Mentions the crossing of their letters. Regrets that Lincoln's bronchitis is acting up. Repeats his request in his previous letter for Lincoln to read a few poems on July 21 at 4 p.m. Mentions having Irving A. Bacheller, Arthur Guiterman and the Bloch Quartet the previous summer and plans to have Walter Trampler, Hans von Kaltenborn and Karl Reiland this year. Says he would be glad to have Lincoln and his wife Florence Sargent Lincoln as his guests for the weekend. Says he will pay Lincoln's traveling expenses. Encloses a leaflet about the restoration of the church.]
  - Hamilton Holt to Joseph Crosby Lincoln, 1940 Jul 5; TLS (carbon), 1 p.
    [Says they have postponed their five Sunday afternoons, which now run from August 18 through September 15. Asks Lincoln to place the four dates, other than the 18th, in order of preference. Hopes Lincoln can take at least half an hour and he will fill the remainder with music. Expresses pleasure at the prospect of having Lincoln and his wife Florence Sargent Lincoln as his house guests.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Hamilton Holt, 1940 Jul 13; TLS, 2 p.
    [Says he hasn't written because of blood pressure problems. Says it is doubtful that he and his wife Florence Sargent Lincoln will be able to come to Woodstock, CT., as his doctor has forbidden public speaking and travel. Says the change of dates might make a difference and that he should know by August 1.]
  - Hamilton Holt to Joseph Crosby Lincoln, 1940 Jul 16; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Expresses sorrow at Joseph Crosby Lincoln's blood pressure problems and says he wouldn't want Joseph Crosby Lincoln to come to Woodstock if it would set him back. Suggests that Joseph Crosby Lincoln speak Sept. 1 and requests permission to list him on that date on a circular. Says he can "give reasons" if it doesn't work out.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Hamilton Holt, 1940 Aug 10; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says he will be unable to come to Woodstock, CT., and may even have to cancel a promised talk in Chatham, MA., as his doctor doesn't want any strain on his throat. Mentions Holt being able to "give the reasons."]
  - Hamilton Holt to Joseph Crosby Lincoln, 1940 Aug 13; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Expresses disappointment at Joseph Crosby Lincoln's letter, but says not one of Lincoln's friends would jeopardize his health. Says he hasn't used Lincoln's name in their announcements. Invites him to come to any of the subsequent Sundays and read a poem or two if he finds he can. Encloses one of the invitations. (no longer with the letter).]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Abraham Saul Burack, 1941 Oct 30; TLS, 1 p.
    [Regrets that he can't contribute a short article to
    The Writer
    in the near future. Mentions not being well and, since the completion of
    The New Hope
    , being forbidden by his doctor to write. Says he must soon begin to think about another story, which will take all his time.]
  - Joseph Crosby Lincoln to Hamilton Holt, 1944 Feb 15; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests reserved seats for himself, his wife Florence Sargent Lincoln, and Mr. and Mrs. Lancaster at an Alexander Procofieff de Seversky talk and picture, health permitting.]
- Photographs
  - Newspaper photo, Joseph Crosby Lincoln, head and shoulder, Photo
  - Photo, signed, Joseph Crosby Lincoln, seated in chair, n.d.; Photo
  - Photo attached to a signed card, Joseph Crosby Lincoln, seated on steps of a cottage, n.d.; Photo
- Miscellaneous
  - Newspaper clipping, obituary of Joseph Crosby Lincoln, from The Boston Herald, [1944] Mar 11; Clipping